# **Tiana Lewis Fraser**

# Industrial Engineer, Lean Six Sigma Trainer, Query Writer, Process Improvement Guru

Wilmington, DE - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Tiana-Lewis-Fraser/9f39dd430f065865

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Senior Industrial Engineer Consultant

CVS Health - Lumberton, NJ - May 2012 to Present

May 2012-Present

- Create and maintain labor management standards for 700 associates in 3 shift operation for largest distribution center
- Lead advising process engineer for E-commerce enterprise initiative
- Prepare and generate weekly logistics update to include financial comparisons to projections and budgets for entire network
- Created MS Access based associate tracking database that included permissions for specific security levels, auto-creation of reports and forms, and established an easily repeatable process for network implementation.
- Perform engineering analysis for continuous improvement projects in logistics network
- Conduct surveys for key business holders to improve efficiencies
- Develop standard operating procedure for all process changes.
- Conduct cost justification analysis for network improvement initiatives

## **Industrial Engineer**

Transfreight - Wilmington, DE - October 2011 to January 2012

Created a new database system to facilitate information storage migration from Excel to Access

- Introduced system automation to a 1200 part Bill of Materials packaging management sheet.
- Developed SQL based program to manipulate and monitor data used for tracking project progress.

#### **Logistics Engineer**

Coty, INC - Sanford, NC - March 2010 to August 2011

for reverse logistics process used as an international company standard designed to reduce footprint by 75%, eliminate use of 3rd party logistics provider, achieve \$1.5 M in annual savings, and be fully integrated in an 8 month time frame.

• Re-Engineered processes for customer crediting in a pre-existing application to reduce cycle time from 1 week to 1 day.

Coordinated with lead supervisors to create standard operating procedures and developed key process indicators to ensure production employees were working to pace.

- Organized third party vendors, contractors, and computer programmers to complete \$150K project on time and under budget.
- Created schedules and time lines to achieve goals within company, safety, and ergonomic industry standards, including safety inspections, security inspections, and chemical handling inspections.
- Trained all end users of system upgrades and warehouse management systems including managers, supervisors, team leads and floor workers, with Standard Operating Procedure documentation.
- Implemented new order picking standards that increased order completion accuracy, minimized audit needs, increased shipping accuracy for outbound dock operations, and created individual key performance measures for floor workers.
- Designed new internal processing facility including floor plans, work station design and set up, and warehouse management integration

For additional skills and information, please visit: www.linkedin.com/pub/tiana-s-lewis-fraser/3b/436/362/

industrial engineer

About

Industrial Engineering professional with 5 years of facility design and process implementation. Project management experience involving multi-million dollar savings for international companies across multiple business streams. Seeking employment to further utilize and build knowledge of industry in an engineering related field.

## **EDUCATION**

## **B.S. in Industrial and Systems Engineering**

North Carolina State Univ - Raleigh, NC April 2010

## **SKILLS**

Statistic modeling, Microsoft Word/ Access/Excel Value Stream Mapping, Microsoft Visio/ SharePoint Database building, SolidWorks / AutoCad 2010 Project management, Lean / Six Sigma training SQL Querying, Financial planning models VBA (Visual Basic), Labor Management Standards

#### **LINKS**

http://www.linkedin.com/pub/tiana-s-lewis-fraser/3b/436/362/